Alexander Parry

14 Greatness Road Sevenoaks Kent

TN14 5BY

07935651741 | natgab14@hotmail.co.uk | www.linkedin.com/in/alex-parry

PROFILE

Versatile professional with extensive experience maintaining engineering equipment and systems in line with established standards. Acknowledged for capacity to analyse issues, expedite innovative solutions, and build the type of consensus-driven environment that contributes to on-time, on-budget delivery.

Now learning and implementing software projects from QA.

KEY SKILLS

- Kent Trainers course in Project Management and Line Management
- The Institution of Occupational Safety and Health (IOSH) course in Managing Safely
- · Working with Microsoft 365/office
- Track record for absorbing volumes of technical and IT information, conceiving realistic solutions, and bridging the gap between technical engineering limitations and management expectations.
- Proven track record of success in managing overall plant operations, leading high-performing teams, offering exceptional management, and maintaining maintenance schedules

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

The OU - Bachelor's degree in Engineering and Technology 2012

Wammitab (COTC)- Thermal treatment of Hazardous waste (clinical waste) 2020

QA software level 3 course (Python, Microsoft Azure, Java, SQL, Bash, HTML)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Service supervisor | BOMAG GB LTD

Nov 2021 to Oct 2022

Heavy Mobile Plant manufacturers

- As a service supervisor; facilitating the work for 10 field service engineers, ensuring parts and service
 kits for the customers, and supporting sales with the pre-delivery inspection of the new machines and
 technology.
- Aided in the delivery of the HS2 machines for the southern part of the HS2 project.

Field technician | Carbon8 solutions

Mar 2021 to Jun 2021

Carbon capturing specialists.

 Worked as a technical and field engineer in France for two months, commissioning a carbon capture cement-producing plant. (Short-term contract) Managed to get the Vikat plant working in France (recycling of cement dust back into road-building materials).

Plant Manager | Stericycle

Mar 2017 to Oct 2020

Clinical waste disposal

- Structure and manage plant production goals. Oversee the two different production areas, maintenance
 crew driving production. Design and implement coaching and training programs to develop staff, facilitate
 efficiency, and improve performance. Liaise with engineering, commercial, and transport team to ensure
 fluid import/export of goods, correct stock control, and improvements of the site. Work within ISO 9001
 and ISO 14001 standards. Spearheaded all associates in production operations with a focus on optimal
 productivity and high standards of quality.
- ullet Successfully implemented the integrated management system, including KPIs.
- Upgraded Q85 shredder using improved, robust planetary gearboxes and replaced the 80 HP motors with IE3 premium efficiency models.
- Developed production systems with maintenance to improve separation streams of raw materials.
- Improved factory and machinery design layout, enabling ease of maintenance and storing of the finished product, stock, etc.
- Developed the maintenance systems, which improved the downtime by 40% and control the stock process and systems.

Shift Manager | SWEEP Kuusakoski

Jan 2015 to Jun 2016

WEEE recycling experts, brown goods and white goods recycling and handling.

- Established and directed plant policies and procedures. Supervised production line operation, improving
 the conveyor belt systems and the materials handling aspect of WEEE separation.
- Achieved maintenance schedules for the machines per the production schedule. Introduced maintenance schedules and improved loss of downtime for production.
- Designed production systems with maintenance to improve separation streams of raw materials.
 Ensured and maintained safety standards to both company and OSHA standards.
- Improved the running performance of the various machines and systems for minimal breakdowns.

Engineering operations manager | Ecologia

Nov 2003 to Jul 2013

Land and water contamination, remediation specialists

- Maintained and repaired company equipment, including drilling rigs and scientific equipment. Facilitated
 day-to-day operations for the engineering department, including project builds, on-site work,
 maintenance, and managing the ISO 9001 and 18001 processes (450001). Prepared health and safety
 documents, including risk assessments and method statements, for engineering works from the design
 process, procurement, and building phases by CDM regulations where applicable
- Designed treatment units for remediation, including steam injection, ozone sparging, soil vapour extraction, bio-slurping, dual-phase extraction, and multi-phase extraction.
- Developed prototypes and designs for site equipment and treatment systems with R&D engineers as well as checked all design drawings before construction.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages – Spanish